netmechanic.com 2007-12-17

# Privacy Statement for www.netmechanic.com

NetMechanic, Inc. which recently became a wholly owned subsidiary of Keynote Systems, Inc. believes that strong electronic privacy is crucial for the ongoing success of the Internet as a service and commercial medium. Please be assured that Keynote, its subsidiaries, and NetMechanic are committed to safeguarding customer privacy on its websites and we know you will feel confident that your identifiable information will be protected when you access our website or order services from us over the Internet. You may find Keynote Systems, Inc's privacy policy at [ http://www.keynote.com/legal/privacy_tpl.html](http://www.keynote.com/legal/privacy_tpl.html).

NetMechanic, Inc. has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to privacy and to outline how we plan to handle such information. The following describes our information gathering and usage practices for [ www.netmechanic.com](http://www.netmechanic.com/). 

**1\. Information NetMechanic gathers and how it is used**

NetMechanic collects data from your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to analyze paths through our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information about our audience which we use to improve the NetMechanic Service (for example, how many international users do we have, how many users use version 3.0 of Netscape, etc). 

NetMechanic issues cookies to users when they come to our Web site to allow us to learn how many unique visitors we have, to aid in analyzing navigation paths through our site, to grant discounts to visitors who elect to take part special promotions, and to maintain login information during a subscriber's session.  Cookie tracking identifies you by using a unique number; personal information such as name and address are only correlated with cookie information to allow us to manage subscriber login sessions.

Other companies which place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign their cookies to you in a process that NetMechanic does not control. However, cookies cannot be used to identify individuals, only machines, so these advertisers will not know who you are - and NetMechanic will not tell them. 

**a.   Subscription Users ** \- NetMechanic's registration form requires users requesting a product or service to give us contact information (such as name, email address, postal address and other data). We use this information to process the order, to infrequently email information on the company (such as a promotional mailing on a new service), and to contact the visitor when necessary. We also collect visitor's financial information (such as a purchase order number or credit card numbers) to bill the user for products and services and for processing credit cards. 

Users may easily opt-out of receiving future mailings by opting out of the newsletter (leaving the checkbox unchecked) or by requesting removal from the newsletter or promotions using any of the methods listed below in the Choice/Opt-Out section.

**b.   Free Users ** \- - When using our free tools, we have a form for the user to enter their URL and email address. The URL is always required because our tool needs that information to know for which site to run a job. The email address is optional for the HTML Toolbox and GIFBot tools. Due to the nature of our other tools an email address is required (for example, with our server monitoring service the email address is needed so we have a way to contact a user about a server problem). Personal data is never released to any third party. 

**c.   All Users ** \- Whether you are a free user or subscription user, you can be assured that if you provide information to NetMechanic, no individual data will passed on to any third-party. NetMechanic will divulge information only as necessary to comply with state and federal laws.

On occasion, NetMechanic conducts online surveys that ask visitors for contact information (like their email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). These surveys are conducted to determine better ways to support our customers. Survey results provide us information that enables us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers better understand the aggregate demographics of our audience. No individual personal data will ever be released from these surveys. Data may be used in aggregate form to learn more about our customers' needs.

NetMechanic may present information to advertisers in the form of aggregate statistics compiled among all of our visitors' answers to survey questions as well as grouped on-site behavior. This is to help our advertisers tailor the content of ads to the interests of our customers. At no time is individual data shared with anyone.

NetMechanic also provides a free email newsletter that covers subjects related to building and maintaining Web sites. Subscription to our newsletter is optional and requires you to reply to a confirmation email indicating your desire to subscribe. Users may opt-in for the newsletter by clicking on the checkbox on the "subscribe to newsletter" option. Users can decline this service by leaving the checkbox unchecked or by choosing not to reply to the confirmation message. If users decide to unsubscribe, it is an easy one step process described in the  Choice/Opt-Out section below.

In addition, NetMechanic provides a Free Monthly Tune Up option that provides users with an automatic free test of their site. Subscription to the Free Monthly Tune Up is optional and requires you to reply to a confirmation email indicating your desire to receive this service. Users may opt-in for their Free Monthly Tune Up by clicking on the checkbox on the "Free Monthly Tune Up" option. Users can decline this service by leaving the checkbox unchecked or by choosing not to reply to the confirmation message. If users decide to unsubscribe, it is an easy one step process described in the  Choice/Opt-Out section below.

NetMechanic may occasionally sponsor a Sweepstakes or contest. In these cases, NetMechanic will require users name, mailing address, and email address. Should you choose to participate, we will notify you via email of the result. Should you be a winner and prize redemption instructions will be sent via postal mail to the address you gave us with your entry form. We will not use your personal information for any other purpose and you will not receive any additional mailings.

NetMechanic occasionally sends informational or promotional mailings related to our services to free users and subscribers. These mailings provide information about our services, and may offer subscription discounts. If a user does not wish to receive this type of information, they may elect to remove their address as described in the  Choice/Opt-Out section below. 

NetMechanic may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what the audience thinks about important issues. NetMechanic uses a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users.

As a subsidiary of Keynote, NetMechanic may also share [your identifiable information] with Keynote and other Keynote subsidiaries to offer you products and services that may be of interest to you. Again, you may elect not to have such information shared for these purposes as described in the  Choice/Opt-Out section below. (Please note that if you have previously responded to an inquiry or notice from NetMechanic regarding this sharing, that the preference expressed by your response will be honored and you do not need to separately Out-Out as described below.)

The NetMechanic Web site contains links to other sites. NetMechanic is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites, as their Privacy Policy may differ from ours.

Although we do have business partners and co branded sites, at no time do we share individual data collected with them. 

**2\. Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Access to computer data and files at NetMechanic, Inc. are secured by password coding to prevent unauthorized access.

NetMechanic utilizes industry standard SSL encryption when accepting your credit card information during our online checkout process. SSL encryption is a method by which information transmitted across the Internet is encoded to defeat theft by anyone who should intercept the data before it reaches its destination. All reputable online stores make use of SSL encryption to request credit card information and other sensitive data from their customers. Web pages where SSL encryption is activated are typically identified by a lock or key symbol displayed somewhere in your browser. 

Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary, and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers.

**3\. Choice/Opt-Out**

NetMechanic provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor. 

  1. Additionally, this site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database or to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our services. You can send email to [ privacy@netmechanic.com](mailto:privacy@netmechanic.com)
  2. You can visit the following URL: http://www.netmechanic.com/remove_mail.htm
  3. If you participate in the Free Monthly Tune Up, you may opt-out by visiting this URL: [ http://r.netmechanic.com/fm/deleteURL.cgi](http://r.netmechanic.com/fm/deleteURL.cgi)
  4. You can send mail to the following postal address:   
NetMechanic, Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Keynote Systems, Inc.   
2100 10th Street   
Suite 500   
Plano, TX 75074

**4.   Corrections/Updates**

NetMechanic gives users the following options for modifying information previously provided. 

  1. You can send email [ privacy@netmechanic.com](mailto:privacy@netmechanic.com)
  2. You can visit the following URL:  http://www.netmechanic.com/login.htm
  3. Subscription services can make changes to their accounts on-line by logging in and selecting the "Change Account Information" link. 
  4. You can send mail to the following postal address:   
NetMechanic, Inc, a wholly owned subsidiary of Keynote Systems, Inc.   
2100 10th Street   
Suite 500   
Plano, TX 75074 
  5. You can call the following telephone number:  
1-877-NET-MECH (1-877-638-6324)  
or 1-972-578-7431 

**5.   Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

**Customer Support**   
NetMechanic, Inc, a wholly owned subsidiary of Keynote Systems, Inc.   
2100 10th Street   
Suite 500   
Plano, TX 75074   
privacy@netmechanic.com   
650-403-2400  
or 1-800-KEYNOTE
